Guide to the Medieval manuscripts: fragment collection, 11-- - 14--, and n.d.
Department of Special Collections
Medieval manuscripts: fragment collection, 11-- - 14--, and n.d.
Special Collections M0297
.25 linear ft. and 1 oversize folder.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Various donors including Albert Bender, 1935 & 1936; Fanny and Philip Duchnes, 1948; and the DeLemos estate, 1962. Some purchases.
Container List
- No provenance information
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 1 *
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 2
  - Bible leaf. Armenia, 15th century., Item 3
  - Psalter. Germany, ca. 15th century., Item 4
- Removed from books in the Rare Book Collections (RBC):
  - Liturgical work with musical signs for chanting. Removed from 473.3 M 517 (Hildebrand Library), n.d., Item 5
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d.Removed from: Petro Bembo, Prose. 1525. RBC KB 1525.B4 f., Item 6 *
- Purchased from Brentano's, Chicago, n.d.:
  - Psalter with commentary, late Carolingian minuscule. Northern France, ca. 1175., Item 7
  - Anonymous devotional treatise, very tiny Gothic script, written in two columns. Italy, ca. 1350., Item 8
  - Dominican Psalter. Antiphona written out in four-line staves in Gregorian notation. Italy, ca. 1400., Item 9
  - Breviary. Round Gothic hand. Italy, ca. 1400., Item 10
  - Psalter. Large Gothic script with music on a four-line stave. England, ca. 1400., Item 11
  - Breviary. Small round Italian book hand. Italy, ca. 1450., Item 12
- Gift of Albert Bender, 1935, 1936:
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 13
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 14
  - De ordinatione ostiariorum, n.d., Item 15
  - From: Book of Offices, musical notation, n.d., Item 16
- Gift of Fanny and Philip Duschnes, 1948:
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., 1440 A.D., Item 17
- Gift of the de Lemos estate, 1962:
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 18
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 19
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 20
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 21
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 22
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 23
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 24
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 25
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 26
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 27
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 28
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 29
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., n.d., Item 30 *
  - Missal. Probably Italy, 15th century., Item 31 *
- OTHER PROVENANCE:
  - Unidentified fragment, n.p., 12-13th century.Purchased, Pregliasco, 1985., Item 32
  - Breviary. Italy, ca. 1480.Gift of the General Bookbinding Company, 1987., Item 33